## **RAJESH K**

Plot no 5b, 3<sup>rd</sup> Street extension, Krishna nagar, Kasbapuram, Chennai – 600 126 +91–9790970599 | rajeshtechkr@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE:

Skilled **Mechanical Engineer** with **5 years** of experience in Plastic product development, Sheet metal design, Casting products development, special purpose machine and also skilled using 3D and 2D CAD software like Solidworks, CATIA, NX and Auto CAD.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES:**

Sheetmetal Design	<ul> <li>Plastic product development</li> </ul>	• Validation of prototypes
<ul> <li>Plastic trims modelling</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Assembly Fixture concept design</li> </ul>	• Layout analysis
Vehicle Integration	<ul> <li>Cross functional team communication</li> </ul>	• SPM Design
• GD&T stackup	<ul> <li>Engineering Change management</li> </ul>	• Problem Solving

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# **Greaves Electric Mobility (Greaves Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Payroll)**

## Design Engineer R&D: December 2022 - Present

- Plastic trims development as per design data received from styling team
- Concept development for plastic enclosures for vehicles
- Create sheetmetal trims from surface data provided
- Prepare 2D drawings for the sheetmetal and plastic parts
- Resolved escalation of vehicle and ergonomics issues
- Investigated and recommended changes in testing and implementation process.
- Review the body and shape of vehicles and recommend user-centered features
- Create and test prototypes of products before implementing them across vehicles.

# Heat and Control (South Asia) Pvt. Ltd.

# Junior CAD Engineer: June 2022 – November 2022

- Create sheetmetal and plastic enclosures and structures required for the food processing and handling equipment.
- Understand the manufacturing capabilities of the shop floor and create sheetmetal products
- Create 3D and 2D files for the developed sheetmetal and plastic design with compliance to standards
- Coordinate with the production team to clear any queries in fabrication.
- Create time estimate for the projects based on resource requirement and nature of work.
- Maintain CAD files in SAP PLM Document Info Record and document structures.

# Changepond Technologies Pvt Ltd., Chennai.

## Senior Engineer Projects: October 2018– June 2022

### Sheetmetal enclosures and Weldment design:

- Designed sheetmetal and Plastic enclosures for electrical cabinets, SPM enclosures and Switch gear cabinets etc.
- Prepare 2D drawings in compliance to the client standards
- E-house design for power distribution lines
- Structural design development as per required standards.

#### **Gear Box Reverse Engineering:**

- Reverse engineering the customer's Gear box input.
- Redesigning gear box from casting to fabrication type.
- The developed gear box casing is provided with required lubrication ports and provisions to support sensors.
- Preparing fabrication drawings for the developed gear box with necessary manufacturing details in accordance to the customer standards.

#### **Casting Products development:**

- Developed 3D models for casting products for various equipments like pump, motors, valves etc.
- Prepared detailed drawings for developed casting models.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

- **B.E. Mechanical Engineering** (2014-2018) with CGPA **7.68** Thangavelu Engineering College (Affiliated to Anna University, Chennai)
- **HSC** 2014 passed out with **84.5%** in Zion Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Selaiyur, Chennai
- **SSLC** 2012 passed out with **89.2%** in Zion Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Selaiyur, Chennai

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

• CAD Software: Solid Works, Autodesk Inventor, AutoCAD, CATIA, NX 12.0

• **PLM software:** SAP in inventor.

• Other Skills: MS PowerPoint, MS Word, MS Excel

## **PERSONAL PROFILE:**

Name Rajesh K

Date of Birth 05-July-1997
Gender & Marital Status Male, Single

**Nationality** Indian

Languages Known English, Tamil

I hereby declare that the above furnished details are true to my consent and knowledge.

Date:RegardsPlace: ChennaiRajesh K